The true story of a heist gone wrong... in all the right ways.
The Bank Job is a thriller, crime, drama film directed by Roger Donaldson.
Terry is a small-time car dealer trying to leave his
shady past behind and start a family.
Martine is a beautiful model from Terry's old
neighbourhood who knows that Terry is no angel.
When Martine proposes a foolproof plan to rob a bank, Terry recognises the
danger but realises this may be the opportunity of a lifetime.
Terry Leather, played by Jason Statham.
Martine Love, played by Saffron Burrows.
Kevin Swain, played by Stephen Campbell Moore.
Dave Shilling, played by Daniel Mays.
Guy Singer, played by James Faulkner.
Quinn, played by Andrew Brooke.
The Bank Job is a 2008 heist thriller film directed by Roger
Donaldson and written by Dick Clement and Ian La Frenais.
It is based on the 1971 burglary of Lloyds Bank
safety deposit boxes in Baker Street.
It stars Jason Statham.
The producers allege that the story was prevented from being told in 1971 because of a
D-Notice, to protect a prominent member of the British royal family.
According to the producers, this film is intended to reveal the truth for the first
time, although it apparently includes significant elements of fiction.
The premiere was held in London on 18 February 2008, and it was released in
the UK on 29 February 2008 and in the US on 7 March 2008.
It received mostly positive reviews from critics
and grossed $66 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of london, england,
blackmail, 1970s, vault, car dealer.
The tone is emotional and intense.